Let's discuss the business case and the
benefits management plan.
So you can go to your PIMBOC, page 30
through 33.
We'll discuss the business case and
benefits management plan in a lot of
detail, but I am in the integration
knowledge area.
So if you want to go to page 77 in your
PIMBOC to follow along, you certainly may.
All right, so the project charter is
normally developed from the business case
so the business case was created prior to
the project it shows the feasibility
justification of the project the need for
the project okay there are many needs
there can be a market demand legal
requirements customer request is most
common you've you have technological
advances, social needs, all kinds of needs
that are bringing a project into fruition,
okay?
There is a need, all right?
It will include the consequences of not
doing the project.
So it shows the feasibility of doing the
project, justification of the project,
also the consequence of not doing the
project.
It might have something to do with
compliance, for example.
So business needs documents the problem or
opportunity and a gap analysis.
How can we get to that opportunity from
where we are?
So current to future states.
And remember the needs assessment is done
prior to the business case itself.
There was a need.
All right.
The business case documents the cost
versus the benefit of the project.
We always want to the benefits to outweigh
the cost of course and does the investment
in that project outweigh the cost what
also is done prior to the project uh based
on the business case will be the benefits
management plan how and when is the
project going to benefit bring value to
the business It's so.
Okay?
So it'll document how
and when the project will
realize the benefits and
how they will be measured.
So it can include target benefits,
whether it's making money, saving money.
It could be to promote goodwill.
A time frame for realizing
the benefits of the project
and how the project aligns
with the organizations.
strategic objectives.
That's always so important.
You don't have a project to just have a
project.
A project is a way to, for the organization
to meet those strategic objectives.
All right, it will also include on the
next slide, benefit owners who,
whether it's the organization,
specific departments, specific
stakeholders, who will actually benefit
from the projects.
all right metrics how the benefits will
actually be realized again most typically
making money saving money and then any
risks uncertainties in actually achieving
those benefits all right so these
documents these are called business
documents are done prior to
the project so they come into the
project our inputs documents
that we will review to get our
project started developing
that project charter